# Megha Girdhar

Address: RL-26 G.F. Gangaramvatika, Tilak Nagar, New Delhi-110018

Email id: megha02girdhar@gmail.com

Contact number- 09870376233

## Career Objective

Highly motivated HR Management graduate having 4+ years of experience seeking a generalist position where I can use my knowledge and expertise in Human Resources to carry out various responsibilities in functional areas such as recruitment, policy implementation and employee relations.

#### Key Skills

Good communication skills Good negotiable skills Multi-tasker People Management Problem solving skills Conflict management

**Professional Experience** 

Last Salary – 22 K Plus 6K (Travel Conveyance) = 28K

Salary Expectations- 35 K- 40 K

Worked with "Bapu Nature Cure Hospital and Yogashram" (Mayur Vihar Phase 1) from May 2017- January 2019 as "Hr Manager"

## Responsibilities:-

Bapu Nature Cure Hospital and Yogashram is 32 years old renowned Naturopathy, Ayurveda, Physiotherapy and Yoga Hospital. It is registered under societies act 1870 with the name as" Nature Cure and Yoga Trust". It is divided in three segments-

- 1. Bapu Nature Cure Hospital and Yogashram- This section is for the patients who belong to various PSUs, DGEHS, CGHS etc.
- 2. BNCHY Wellness Medispa- This is the private section mainly for private patients consultation and treatment and also we have spa treatments/therapies like Swedish massage, Balinese massage, Thai Massage, Hot stone massage etc.
- 3. LBI Academy- Inaugurated by Sh. Giriraj Singh (Minister of Micro, Small and Medium Enterprises) is mainly imparting training to the unemployed youth, women and transgender in the field of Yoga, Spa, Naturopathy and Ayurveda.

My profile was of "HR Manager" wherein I was the only person responsible for the entire management of the Human Resources for the 3 segments. My roles and responsibilities are as follows:

- 1. Recruitment of human resources (Screening, interviewing and short listing the candidates for the profiles mentioned below)- Job portals that were being used Naukri.com and Indeed.com. Also considering the trainees, walk-ins and references for the positions vacant.
- 1. Naturopathy Doctor
- 2. Ayurveda Doctor
- 3. Front Office Executive
- 4. Shop Assistant
- 5. Accounts Executive
- 6. Housekeeping/Security (Through vendors (Outsourcing))
- 7. Office Boy
- 8. Yoga Trainer
- 9. Training and Placement Head (Academy)
- 10. Soft Skills Trainer (Academy)
- 11. Spa Therapists
- 12.Spa Manager
- 13. Naturopathy and Ayurveda Therapists (Both Male and Female)
- 2. Induction training of the employee (On-going training programmes)
- 3. Documenting the terminations, absence, performance appraisals etc.
- 4. Resolving conflicts (Employee grievances)
- 5. Managing the attendance data (Matrix Attendance System Punch-in attendance system)
- 6. Salary management (Without PF/ESI (outsourced))
- 7. Background checks (Verifications) through calls, emails etc.
- 8. TPA- Handling the Hospital Empanelment with various PSU's like Power Finance Corporation, Power Grid Corp., NTPC, GAIL, CPCB etc., Fresh/Renewal of the empanelments
- 9. Was actively conducting the health camps and workshops (Free and Paid Both) at hospital and companies (Public Sector and Private Sector)

- 10.Looking after the registration agreements of the academy under projects like DDUGKY, HSBC Skills for Life-2019 etc.
- 11. Enrolling the candidates of NDDY, BNYS, BAMS, PGDYS, DYS, DNYS courses for internships under the concerned doctors
- 12. Creating Training Programs under the guidance of Medical Superintendent, Senior Doctors and Academy Head
- 13. Setting up the standard HRM Policy (HRM Manuals)

Worked with "Tathvik Enterprises" From "Oct. 2015 to April 2017" as a HR cum Admin executive

#### Responsibilities:-

- ✓ Recruiting, interviewing and short listing candidates for various posts such as-
  - Collection cum delievery boy
  - Tele-caller
  - Receptionist
  - Office boy (peon)
  - Security guard
  - Driver etc
  - ✓ Induction training of the employees.
  - ✓ Documentation of the personal records, joining formalities, absence, exit formalities etc.
  - ✓ Maintain stationary, petty cash etc.

Worked with "Sky InfoTech Pvt. Ltd." from July 2014 to Sept. 2015 as a Hr cum Public Relation Officer

This company is a training company that provides training into the IT courses such as JAVA, DOT NET, SAP, PHP etc.

#### Responsibilities:

- ✓ Calling the interested candidates through the generated leads
- ✓ Counseling the candidates for the particular course they are interested for Following up the candidates after their visit
- ✓ Recruitments and interviewing the candidates for various profiles

#### Education

- Post Graduation Diploma in Business Management (Human Resource Management)
  Lancaster University, UK (GD Goenka World Institute, 2012-2014)- 65%
- Bachelor of Technology in Biomedical Engineering (Maharashi Dayanand University, Rohtak)- 2008-2012 -70%
- 12<sup>th</sup> (Cambridge Foundation School, Rajouri Garden)- 2008-67%
- 10<sup>th</sup> (Cambridge Foundation School, Rajouri Garden)-2006-75%

## Internships

### PNB BANK (PGDBM HR)-

Understanding the functions of various departments (IRD, MRD, SMRD, Recruitment, Selection)

Gone through the policies and practices of the organisation Participated in

the Recruitment Process

FORTIS JESSARAM HOSPITAL (BIOMEDICAL ENGG)-Trained in Biomedical Department

Handled day to day issues related to the various equipments in the organisation (Troubleshooting)

Studied about various machines (X-RAY, CT SCAN, MRI, EQUIPMENTS N OT, SUCTION MACHINE) in the hospitals

DEEN DYAL UPADHAYA HOSPITAL(BIOMEDICAL ENGG.)-Trained in Biomedical Department

Handled day to day issues related to the various equipments in the organisation (Troubleshooting)

Studied about various machines in the hospitals

Familiar Operating Systems: Windows XP, Windows Vista, Win 7.

Application Software: MS-Office. 2003, MS Office 2008 Good

Knowledge of Internet

## **Personal Details:**

Father's Name Mr. Mantosh Girdhar

Marital Status-Single

D.O.B- 2<sup>nd</sup> October 1991

Hobby- Listening to music & reading boo